Office of University Counsel Records UA148
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Office of University Counsel Records
1994 -- 1999
1984 -- 2019
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
University Relations Division
University Counsel
UA148
9.6 Linear Feet 8 boxes
1 Digital Object(s)
128 Kilobytes
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into two series: Chronological Correspondence Files and 2020 accessions.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains the chronological correspondence files from the Office of General Counsel, specifically Mary Lee Jacobs, and documents related to the transfer of the Tufts Cannon from the United States Navy to Tufts.
Biographical / Historical
The Office of University Counsel coordinates the delivery of all legal services on behalf of Tufts University.
As in-house counsel, this office provides advice and support to the University's administrative and academic personnel on a broad range of matters, including employee relations, real estate transactions, contracts, subpoena compliance, litigation and policy development.
The Office of University Counsel is part of the University Relations Division. The three arms of the division are the Office of the University Counsel, the Office of Community and Government Relations, and the Office of Communications.
Conditions Governing Access
Records containing information related to student education, staff and faculty employment, and Board of Trustees records are closed for 75 years from the date of creation.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains correspondence and memos from the Office of the University Counsel.
Legal and Regulatory; University Relations; Employment and Human Resources
- Chronological Correspondence Files, 1984 -- 2004; 1994 -- 1999; UA148.001; 9.6 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  Materials were created when Mary Lee Jacobs was General Counsel for the University.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged chronologically.
  Conditions Governing Access
  75 years from the date of creation.
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, March 6-May 10, 1984; UA148.001.001.00001 (Box 1)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, May 4-Sept 25, 1984; UA148.001.001.00002 (Box 1)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, May 11-June 28, 1984; UA148.001.001.00003 (Box 1)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, Sept. 26-Dec. 21, 1984; UA148.001.001.00004 (Box 1)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, letters, March 2-July 6, 1984; UA148.001.001.00005 (Box 1)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, letters, July 6-Dec. 20, 1984; UA148.001.001.00006 (Box 1)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, Jan. 2-April 16, 1985; UA148.001.001.00007 (Box 1)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, April 16-Aug. 27, 1985; UA148.001.001.00008 (Box 1)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, May 14-Dec. 31, 1985; UA148.001.001.00009 (Box 1)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, Sept. 3-Oct. 31, 1985; UA148.001.001.00010 (Box 1)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, Nov. 4-Dec. 31, 1985; UA148.001.001.00011 (Box 1)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, letters, Jan. 2-May 13, 1985; UA148.001.001.00012 (Box 1)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, Jan. 6-May 15, 1986; UA148.001.001.00013 (Box 1)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, May 1-July 7, 1986; UA148.001.001.00014 (Box 1)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, July 7-July 30, 1986; UA148.001.001.00015 (Box 1)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, Aug. 1-Oct. 2, 1986; UA148.001.001.00016 (Box 1)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, Oct. 6-Dec. 24, 1986; UA148.001.001.00017 (Box 1)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, letters, Jan. 6-Aug. 1, 1986; UA148.001.001.00018 (Box 1)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, letters, July 22-Oct. 31, 1986; UA148.001.001.00019 (Box 1)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, letters, Nov. 3-Dec. 23, 1986; UA148.001.001.00020 (Box 1)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, Jan. 5-April 16, 1987; UA148.001.001.00021 (Box 1)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, April 21-June 29, 1987; UA148.001.001.00022 (Box 1)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, July 2-Oct. 8, 1987; UA148.001.002.00001 (Box 2)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, July 23-Oct. 8, 1987; UA148.001.002.00002 (Box 2)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, Oct. 8-Dec.23, 1987; UA148.001.002.00003 (Box 2)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, letters, Jan. 6-April 8, 1987; UA148.001.002.00004 (Box 2)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, letters, April 9-June 29, 1987; UA148.001.002.00005 (Box 2)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, letters, Oct. 8-Dec. 23, 1987; UA148.001.002.00006 (Box 2)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, Jan. 4-Feb. 22, 1988; UA148.001.002.00007 (Box 2)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, June 28-Sept. 21, 1988; UA148.001.002.00008 (Box 2)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, July 20-Sept. 1, 1988; UA148.001.002.00009 (Box 2)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, Sept. 21-Dec. 19, 1988; UA148.001.002.00010 (Box 2)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, Nov. 14-Dec. 21, 1988; UA148.001.002.00011 (Box 2)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, letters, Jan. 5-Feb. 16, 1988; UA148.001.002.00012 (Box 2)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, letters, Jan. 19-June 28, 1988; UA148.001.002.00013 (Box 2)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, letters, Feb. 22-June 30, 1988; UA148.001.002.00014 (Box 2)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, letters, July 5-July 20, 1988; UA148.001.002.00015 (Box 2)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, letters, Sept. 1-Nov. 10, 1988; UA148.001.002.00016 (Box 2)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, Jan. 4-March 14, 1989; UA148.001.002.00017 (Box 2)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, Jan. 23-May 2, 1989; UA148.001.002.00018 (Box 2)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, Jan. 23-May 4, 1989; UA148.001.002.00019 (Box 2)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, March 16-April 24, 1989; UA148.001.002.00020 (Box 2)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, May 1-June 29, 1989; UA148.001.003.00001 (Box 3)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, July 6-Sept. 7, 1989; UA148.001.003.00002 (Box 3)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, Sept. 8-Dec. 27, 1989; UA148.001.003.00003 (Box 3)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, letters, July 7-Oct. 13, 1989; UA148.001.003.00004 (Box 3)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, letters, Oct. 16-Dec. 21, 1989; UA148.001.003.00005 (Box 3)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, Jan. 18-April 23, 1990; UA148.001.003.00006 (Box 3)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, April 5-June 28, 1990; UA148.001.003.00007 (Box 3)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, April 23-June 28, 1990; UA148.001.003.00008 (Box 3)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, July 6-Sept. 4, 1990; UA148.001.003.00009 (Box 3)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, July 6-Oct. 12, 1990; UA148.001.003.00010 (Box 3)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, Sept. 5-Nov. 16, 1990; UA148.001.003.00011 (Box 3)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, Nov. 16-Dec. 20, 1990; UA148.001.003.00012 (Box 3)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, letters, Jan. 2-April 4, 1990; UA148.001.003.00013 (Box 3)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, letters, Oct. 17-Dec. 20, 1990; UA148.001.003.00014 (Box 3)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, Jan. 2-March 18, 1991; UA148.001.003.00015 (Box 3)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, March 20-June 28, 1991; UA148.001.003.00016 (Box 3)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, July 3-Oct. 9, 1991; UA148.001.003.00017 (Box 3)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, Oct. 16-Dec. 20, 1991; UA148.001.003.00018 (Box 3)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, letters, Jan. 4-March 29, 1991; UA148.001.003.00019 (Box 3)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, letters, April 1-June 27, 1991; UA148.001.003.00020 (Box 3)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, letters, July 8-Oct. 10, 1991; UA148.001.003.00021 (Box 3)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, letters, Oct. 11-Dec. 20, 1991; UA148.001.004.00001 (Box 4)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, Jan. 1-Sept. 3, 1992; UA148.001.004.00002 (Box 4)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, Jan. 7-April 13, 1992; UA148.001.004.00003 (Box 4)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, Jan. 7- April 21, 1992; UA148.001.004.00004 (Box 4)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, April 13-June 30, 1992; UA148.001.004.00005 (Box 4)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, April 23-June 30, 1992; UA148.001.004.00006 (Box 4)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, Sept. 8-Nov. 4, 1992; UA148.001.004.00007 (Box 4)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, Sept. 16-Nov. 13, 1992; UA148.001.004.00008 (Box 4)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, Nov. 5-Dec. 22, 1992; UA148.001.004.00009 (Box 4)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, letters, July 1-Sept. 14, 1992; UA148.001.004.00010 (Box 4)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, letters, Nov. 19-Dec. 22, 1992; UA148.001.004.00011 (Box 4)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, Jan. 5-April 2, 1993; UA148.001.004.00012 (Box 4)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, Jan. 6-Feb. 24, 1993; UA148.001.004.00013 (Box 4)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, Feb. 24-May 11, 1993; UA148.001.004.00014 (Box 4)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, April 5-June 30, 1993; UA148.001.004.00015 (Box 4)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, July 1-Oct. 15, 1993; UA148.001.004.00016 (Box 4)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, Oct. 15-Dec. 22, 1993; UA148.001.004.00017 (Box 4)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, letters, May 11-June 30, 1993; UA148.001.004.00018 (Box 4)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, letters, June 30-Sept. 17, 1993; UA148.001.005.00001 (Box 5)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, letters, Sept. 21-Nov. 1, 1993; UA148.001.005.00002 (Box 5)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, letters, Nov. 3-Dec. 23, 1993; UA148.001.005.00003 (Box 5)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, Jan. 3-Feb. 23, 1994; UA148.001.005.00004 (Box 5)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, Feb. 28-April 20, 1994; UA148.001.005.00005 (Box 5)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, April 26-June 28, 1994; UA148.001.005.00006 (Box 5)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, July 1-Sept. 8, 1994; UA148.001.005.00007 (Box 5)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, Sept. 7-Oct. 28, 1994; UA148.001.005.00008 (Box 5)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, Oct. 31-Dec. 22, 1994; UA148.001.005.00009 (Box 5)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, letters, Jan. 5- Mar. 9, 1994; UA148.001.005.00010 (Box 5)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, letters, Mar. 9-May 9, 1994; UA148.001.005.00011 (Box 5)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, letters, May 6-June 28, 1994; UA148.001.005.00012 (Box 5)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, letters, July 11-Oct. 4, 1994; UA148.001.005.00013 (Box 5)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, letters, Oct. 5-Nov. 22, 1994; UA148.001.005.00014 (Box 5)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, letters, Nov. 23-Dec. 27, 1994; UA148.001.005.00015 (Box 5)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, Jan. 11-Feb. 1, 1995; UA148.001.005.00016 (Box 5)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, Feb. 1-May 10, 1995; UA148.001.005.00017 (Box 5)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, April 13-May 15, 1995; UA148.001.005.00018 (Box 5)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, May 16-June 29, 1995; UA148.001.005.00019 (Box 5)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, July 10-Aug. 9, 1995; UA148.001.005.00020 (Box 5)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, Aug. 21-Sept. 29, 1995; UA148.001.006.00001 (Box 6)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, Sept 29.-Oct. 31, 1995; UA148.001.006.00002 (Box 6)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, Nov. 1-Nov. 28, 1995; UA148.001.006.00003 (Box 6)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, Nov. 29-Dec. 21, 1995; UA148.001.006.00004 (Box 6)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, letters, Jan. 3-Mar. 8, 1995; UA148.001.006.00005 (Box 6)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, letters, Mar. 8-April 20, 1995; UA148.001.006.00006 (Box 6)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, letters, April 20-June 30, 1995; UA148.001.006.00007 (Box 6)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, letters, June 30-Aug. 10, 1995; UA148.001.006.00008 (Box 6)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, letters, Aug. 10-Sept. 18, 1995; UA148.001.006.00009 (Box 6)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, letters, Sept. 18-Oct. 30, 1995; UA148.001.006.00010 (Box 6)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, letters, Nov. 6-Dec. 21, 1995; UA148.001.006.00011 (Box 6)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, Jan. 2-Feb. 15, 1996; UA148.001.006.00012 (Box 6)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, Feb. 20-Mar. 19, 1996; UA148.001.006.00013 (Box 6)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, Mar. 19-May 9, 1996; UA148.001.006.00014 (Box 6)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, May 9-May 31, 1996; UA148.001.006.00015 (Box 6)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, June 3-June 26, 1996; UA148.001.006.00016 (Box 6)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, July 1-Sept. 9, 1996; UA148.001.006.00017 (Box 6)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, Sept. 10-Oct. 24, 1996; UA148.001.006.00018 (Box 6)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, Oct. 28-Dec. 18, 1996; UA148.001.006.00019 (Box 6)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, letters, Jan. 2-Feb. 14, 1996; UA148.001.007.00001 (Box 7)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, letters, Feb. 14-April 8, 1996; UA148.001.007.00002 (Box 7)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, letters, April 8-May 31, 1996; UA148.001.007.00003 (Box 7)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, letters, June 4-June 26, 1996; UA148.001.007.00004 (Box 7)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, letters, July 3-Dec. 19, 1996; UA148.001.007.00005 (Box 7)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, Jan. 6-April 3, 1997; UA148.001.007.00006 (Box 7)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, April 3-May 29, 1997; UA148.001.007.00007 (Box 7)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, May 30-June 30, 1997; UA148.001.007.00008 (Box 7)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, July 1-Sept. 18, 1997; UA148.001.007.00009 (Box 7)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, Sept. 23-Nov. 12, 1997; UA148.001.007.00010 (Box 7)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, Nov. 17-Dec. 22, 1997; UA148.001.007.00011 (Box 7)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, letters, Jan. 13-June 30, 1997; UA148.001.007.00012 (Box 7)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, letters, July 1-Dec. 17, 1997; UA148.001.007.00013 (Box 7)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, Jan. 6-March 4, 1998; UA148.001.007.00014 (Box 7)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, Mar. 5-June 30, 1998; UA148.001.007.00015 (Box 7)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, July 2-Oct. 15, 1998; UA148.001.007.00016 (Box 7)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, Oct. 20-Dec. 16, 1998; UA148.001.007.00017 (Box 7)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, letters, Jan. 26-June 29, 1998; UA148.001.007.00018 (Box 7)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, letters, July 2-Dec. 15, 1998; UA148.001.007.00019 (Box 7)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, Jan. 4-April 12, 1999; UA148.001.007.00020 (Box 7)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, April 12-June 30, 1999; UA148.001.007.00021 (Box 7)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, July 2-Nov. 23, 1999; UA148.001.007.00022 (Box 7)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, Nov. 29-Dec. 22, 1999; UA148.001.007.00023 (Box 7)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, letters, Jan. 7-Dec. 16, 1999; UA148.001.008.00001 (Box 8)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, Jan. 5-Mar. 2, 2000; UA148.001.008.00002 (Box 8)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, Mar. 6-June 29, 2000; UA148.001.008.00003 (Box 8)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, July 6-Oct. 27, 2000; UA148.001.008.00004 (Box 8)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, Oct. 30-Dec. 18, 2000; UA148.001.008.00005 (Box 8)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, letters, Jan. 4-Dec. 18, 2000; UA148.001.008.00006 (Box 8)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, Jan. 2-Feb. 27, 2001; UA148.001.008.00007 (Box 8)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, Feb. 28-June 26, 2001; UA148.001.008.00008 (Box 8)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, July 3-Dec. 21, 2001; UA148.001.008.00009 (Box 8)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, letters, Jan. 2-Dec. 20, 2001; UA148.001.008.00010 (Box 8)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, Jan. 3-June 25, 2002; UA148.001.008.00011 (Box 8)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, July 2-Oct. 16, 2002; UA148.001.008.00012 (Box 8)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, Oct. 18-Dec. 20, 2002; UA148.001.008.00013 (Box 8)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, letters, Jan. 11-Dec. 4, 2002; UA148.001.008.00014 (Box 8)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, Jan. 6-April 1, 2003; UA148.001.008.00015 (Box 8)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, April 9-June 25, 2003; UA148.001.008.00016 (Box 8)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, July 2-Nov. 4, 2003; UA148.001.008.00017 (Box 8)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, Nov. 5-Dec. 18, 2003; UA148.001.008.00018 (Box 8)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, letters, Jan. 9-Dec. 17, 2003; UA148.001.008.00019 (Box 8)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, memos, Jan. 5-April 1, 2004; UA148.001.008.00020 (Box 8)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, letters, Feb. 10-April 8, 2004; UA148.001.008.00021 (Box 8)
- 2020 accessions, 2019; UA148.000167; 128 Kilobytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object containing 2 files.
  20 years from date of creation.
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Transferred by Office of General Counsel, 2019, accession UA-2020-020.
  Documents related to the transfer of the Tufts Cannon from the U.S. Navy to Tufts University.
  - Replica cannon transfer agreement and thank you letters, 2019 August 29 -- 2019 September 04; UA148.000168; 128 Kilobytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object containing 2 files.